

Professional Summary

I am IT specialist with more then 20 years of experience in software development. I am hardworking, team and goal oriented, challenge seeking, and work well under pressure.

- Hardware Builds

- System Audits

- Stuff Management

- Information Security

- Hardware maintenance

- Microfinance software

My experience includes:

- Project Management

- Network Design/Deployment/Administration/Maintenance

- System Administration

- LAN/WAN/Wireless

- Backup/Recovery Plans

- Network Security

- WEB applications/sites development

- Programming with Object Oriented programs, such as Visual Basic 6.0 / .NET, PHP

- Client/Server application development and design using Visual Basic 6.0

- Database design, implementation, administration and maintenance using the Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, IBM DB2

- Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer

- Microsoft Certified System Administrator

Technical Skills

- Hardware/OS: Windows, Windows servers- Software: VB 6.0/NET, Transact SQL,

PHP, Laravel, JS, VUE.js, Joomla, WordPress, CSS, SASS, Tailwind CSS, HTML, GIT

- Databases: MS SQL Server, MS Access, IBM DB2, MySQL, Firebase

- Networking: Microsoft Network with Windows Servers

Professional Experience

Reference project: Vue.js, Firebase (e-commerce site with stripe payment: https://vue-ecommerce-9894c.firebaseapp.com/) Portfolio project: React.js, Firebase and some Node.js backend (e-commerce site at: https://e-comme-live.herokuapp.com/) Work in progress:

Donau trade: Changing old joomla web site to new one + web app for projects/meetings (backend api in php/mysql, Laravel framework, frontend in VUE.js, bootstrap4). (github: https://github.com/nijepa/laravel-vue)

Jinran trading: Web aplication for business (github: https://github.com/nijepa/jinran), using PHP/MySQL (Laravel framework), VUE.js, CSS (in testing stage, needs content review).

ZD Elektronik: Custom MVC web site, using PHP/MySQL, JS, CSS (github: https://github.com/nijepa/zde) (finished, will be online soon).

IT Manager for MicroFinS /Non-Government Microfinance Organization, with UNHCR as one of Donors (2002-2018)

My role is to project information system, administer and maintain several databases, develop several applications (for salaries, bookkeeping, human resources), provide assistance in the creation of various reports, hardware and network project, design and maintenance, troubleshooting and installation. (System and database Engineer/Administrator & Programmer).

I was involved in two MFI software suites, kredits and aspekt. For the second one I was Project Manager from the begining of implementation (2013-2014). I also develop Web sites at www.microfins.org.rs (Joomla).

Used: Visual Basic 6.0 for sofware development, MS SQL Server 2015 and MS Access for database design, MS Excell for reports.

Network: Windows 2008/2012 Servers, Windows XP/7 workstations, wireles and local area network, Internet.

Project management: Redmine

Reference: Braco Saša Dimitrovski, CEO (bracods@microfins.org.rs)

Donautrade (2001-present)

As a associate. Projecting and implementing of network, hardware and software environment. Programming several applications (Warehouse, Bookkeeping, Invoicing).

Used: Visual Basic 6.0 for sofware development, MS Access for database design, MS Excell for reports.

Network: Windows 2008/2012 Servers, Windows XP/7 workstations, wireles and local area network, Internet.

I also develop Web sites at www.donau.rs, www.donau.rs, www.donau.rs, www.donau.rs, www.donau.rs, www.donau.rs), <a href

Reference: Nemanja Ranđić, CEO (randjicn@donautrade.rs)

NIT Solutions (2005-2015)

As a associate. Projecting and implementing of network environment, programming several applications (Expense tracking system, System for production, warehouse, invoicing, buying analysis and sales)

Used: Visual Basic 6.0 for sofware development, MS Access for database design, MS Excell for reports.

Network: Windows 2008 Servers, Windows XP/Vista/7 workstations, wireles and local area network, Internet.

Reference: Zoran Novaković, CEO (hans@nit-solutions.net)

NTE Engineering Beograd (2001-2002)

Participation in developing several two- and three-tier client/server applications. The applications were for the system of parking lots, ticket counter, cash desk.

Used: Visual Basic 6.0 for sofware development, MS SQL Server 2000 for database design.

Reference: Srđan Vuković, CEO (srvukovic@sezampro.rs)

Application Software Partner (2001)

Involved in the programming, analysis and design of three-tier client/server application as a associate. The application is for stock market.

Used: Transact SQL for writing Stored Procedures, MS SQL Server 2000 for database design.

Reference: Zvonko Milosavljević, CEO (asp@eunet.rs)

AD Jugopetrol Kotor (1996-2001)

Participation in a team whose job was to create an informative center for that company. Our job was to install, test end edit software, project, design and prepair the network and hardware and make web site and intranet, of course maintance also. We worked on the programming language »IAF«, that was generated from C++ and have a syntax like VBA and some other programming languages, like Visual Basic, FoxPro, MS Access, Transact SQL. Our job was also to project, create and maintain databases on the SQL Server 2000.

Reference: Vasko Petrović, Director of IT sector (vasko.petrovic@jugopetrol.me)

(1996-Present)

I also developed aplications for a number of Clients in Visual Basic on MS Access databases, and web-sites (PHP, Joomla, WordPress):

- Pamex, Bostek (app for warehouse, invoicing)

Reference: Slobodan, Director (office@pamex.me)

- Cigre (app for organisation of meetings)

Reference: Julija Spajić, Director (office@cigresrbija.rs)

- Farman (app for warehouse, invoicing)

Reference: Damir Mandić, Director (damirm@me)

- Dom Zdravlja Kotor (app for employee records, scheduling reviews)

Reference: Mira Pavićević, Accountant (bagzi7@yahoo.com)

- CiclodroM (app for warehouse, invoicing)

Reference: Aleksandar Bogojević, Director (ciclodrom@hotmail.com)

- SpajicCo (app for warehouse, invoicing)

Reference: Darko Spajić, Director (spajicco@eunet.rs)

- Krypton (app for warehouse, invoicing)

Reference: Dejan Vasiljević, Director (office@krypton.co.rs)

- Etno Salon (app for warehouse, invoicing)

Reference: Nemanja Ranđić, Director (randja@gmail.com)

- Lepota na sprat (site www.lepotanasprat.com (WordPress))
- Profesorska kolonija (site www.profesorskakolonija.rs (WordPress))

•••

Education:

1991-1996 »Higher Business School«, at the Informatic department (in title of Informatic Engineer) in Belgrade, Serbia.

2006-2008 <u>»The Faculty of Business Information Science«</u>, at the Projecting and Programming of the Information Systems department (in title of Dipl. Engineer for Projecting and Programming of the Information Systems) in Belgrade, Serbia.

Courses undertaken

 $September\ 2001\ \underline{Microsoft}\ Certified\ Solutions\ Developer\ (Visual\ Basic\ 6.0,\ SQL\ Server\ 2000)$

December 2003 Microsoft Certified System Administrator (Windows 2003 Server, Windows XP)

May 2020 Udemy - Laravel API Development & Vue JS SPA from Scratch

May 2020 <u>freeCodeCamp</u> - <u>Responsive Web Design</u>

Biography:

- Date of birth: April 9, 1972- Place of birth: Kotor, Montenegro

- Address: Kornelija Stankovica 4, Belgrade

- Country: Serbia

Phone: 00381 11 3088 648
Mobile: 00381 64 1836 034
Languages: English, Italian

Contact:

- E-mail: <u>nijepa@gmail.com</u>

- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikola-pavicevic-43924221/

- GitHub: https://github.com/nijepa